Guide to the Papers of Harrison Salisbury,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Box Listing (unsorted)
  - Salisbury, A. H. Miscellaneous, 1867-1901, (Receipts, Bills, Deeds ) (Box 436, Folder 7)
  - Salisbury, A. H. Bellevue Hospital 1866, Michigan 1865: A H Salisbury's attendance at, (Medical Cards ) (Box 436, Folder 8)
  - Salisbury, Mary Pitchard Pritchard Family, 1865-1914, (Letters, Packets, Genealogical Material ) (Box 436, Folder 9)
  - Salisbury, Percy Letters, Book, Antique Valentine Cards, Percy's Autograph: From and to his father (as a child), 1874-1988 (Box 436, Folder 10)
  - Dad's Birth: AHS about - original (in pieces, bottom seems to be missing) and typed copy, (Letter ) (Box 436, Folder 11)
  - Salisbury, A. H. Letters: To and from AHS and some others, 1861-1900 (Box 436, Folder 12)
  - Pritchard Genealogy, "Unk" Pension and Service Record (Box 437, Folder 13)
  - Evans - Milller Families, GES, 1930s, (Correspondence, Notes, Documents ) (Box 437, Folder 14)
  - Rink Family Records, 1930s, 1950s, (Letters, Correspondence ) (Box 437, Folder 15)
  - Salisbury, A. H. Announcements of U. Of Wisconsin, 1861-1965 (Box 437, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous: Non-Salisbury Journal of 1866 Prairie Wagon to Montana (Box 437, Folder 17)
  - Salisbury, J. E. Letters: JES to GES in New York, 1947-1949 (Box 438, Folder 1)
  - Letters: To Georgia: (1) re bust-up of marriage (2) from Aunt Sarah Miller, Uncle Albert's wife (3) to Maria Evans, largely responses to Geo's wedding, 1906 (Box 438, Folder 2)
  - Janet's School Record, (Photos ) (Box 438, Folder 3)
  - The Salisburian: A Genealogical Magazine: Vol. II, Nos. 1 (Jan. 1924) - 6 (Apr. 1928) (Box 438, Folder 4)
  - Janet Before 12, (Poetry, School Assignments, Other Writing ) (Box 439, Folder 5)
  - Mike to GES, 1940s, (Mementoes ) (Box 439, Folder 8)
  - Artifacts: U. of Wisconsin Commencement program, 1870 -- Concert program, Minneapolis, 1903 -- Cut-out pen and ink drawing of Dr. A. H. Salisbury -- Essay on "Our Flag" (handwritten in brown ink, author and date unknown) -- English translation of Dutch deed for Manhattan -- Pressed flowers (Box 439, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous WWI Mostly WWI, but up to 1937 -- "Summer Retreat" (Box 439, Folder 12)
  - Postcards, Greeting Cards: To Salisbury from Russia and other foreign parts, 1950s, 1960s (Box 439, Folder 13)
  - Early Pritchard and Salisbury: Mazomanie labelled. Includes envelope of ,"Evansville 1915", (Negatives, Photos ) (Box 440, Folder 16)
  - Old Salisbury: Mostly identified -- Includes Percy Salisbury grade, U. of Minnesota, 1889, (Book, Photos ) (Box 440, Folder 17)
  - Salisbury, Sue M. Photos: Some on metal, (Photographs) (Box 440, Folder 18)
  - Salisbury Family Pictures: Mostly DeWitt and Orelia -- some undated, 1882-1904, (Photographs ) (Box 440, Folder 20)
  - Sue's Collection: Some prints on metal, ca. 1895, (Photographs Notebook, Photos ) (Box 440, Folder 21)
  - Maps, Photos, Notes, Sketches, (Photographs) (Box 440, Folder 22)
  - Trip to East, 1922, (Photographs Snapshots ) (Box 440, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Studio: 8 x 10, b&w of Jackie Coogan in "Oliver Twist", blond boy (possibly Coogan) dressed as Indian in play, unidentified man in navy uniform, (Photographs Photos ) (Box 440, Folder 24)
  - Mostly JES and Salisbury as children, (Photographs Snapshots, Negatives, Photos ) (Box 441, Folder 25)
  - Sue's WWI Mementoes: Uniform pieces and insignia, purse with service pins, bag of toy soldiers, etc. (Box 441, Folder 26)
  - Campaign Buttons: In envelope, mostly Red Cross, Liberty Bonds, etc. (Box 441, Folder 27)
  - JES to Sue Salisbury, 1937, (Letters ) (Box 439, Folder 6)
  - Pentagon Pentagon Papers, (Invitation, Cards, GES Wedding Certificate, Present List, Guest List, Telegram ) (Box 439, Folder 7)
  - Sue M. Salisbury Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1925-1948 (Box 439, Folder 10)
  - A H Salisbury Commencement Address At U. of Wisconsin, Madison re commencement -- Note to Salisbury from JES, 1984 (Box 439, Folder 11)
  - Sue M. Salisbury WWI: Almost entirely French. Incl. other souvenir of WWI, (Cards, Postcards, Photographs ) (Box 439, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous: Including Gordon Roth, Jim Brown (in uniform with airplane -- WWII), with Salisbury, (Photographs, Snapshots, Studio Portraits, Group Shots ) (Box 440, Folder 15)
  - Georgiana Salisbury Photos: Includes wedding, 1892-1907, (Photographs) (Box 440, Folder 19)
  - Sue Salisbury WWI: Fom France, in envelopes -- [Notes, etc. --not numbered or in folders: GES Note of Trip East 1922 -- Sue Salisbury address, WWI Period -- Unidentified address (brown cover, gold) -- A H Salisbury account, Irish-American Bank of Minneapolis -- Janet Salisbury Diary 1922 (maroon cover, with title "Record") -- "Janet Salisbury, 107 Royalston AV. NO.", School Note -- Percy Salisbury's School Note -- School Note with names Susie M. Salisbury and Janet Salisbury -- Address/Account (unidentified owner) -- black ring binder with alphabet dividers, entries cA. 1937-40 ]-- [REMOVED: Ledger, A. E. Ames, M.D., Minneapolis (partner of AHSalisbury) -- Ledger -- unidentified, but same binding as Ames ledger -- Bible -- NY: Carlton and Porter, 1860 -- Evan D. J. Evans stamped on front -- Miscellaneous papers between Old and New Testamnents, (Photographs, Negatives, Letters, Book ) (Box 441, Folder 28)
  - China And The Western Powers: Paper by GES for Electives Club, undated (19 pp.) (Box 442, Folder 1)
  - In Memory of the Deceased Members of the Century Club -- Judge Hooker and DR. Salisbury, (Document ) (Box 442, Folder 2)
  - Awards, Etchigh School Diploma, Fraternity & Boy Scout Certificates, JES High School Diploma: Including Eagle Scout (Box 442, Folder 3)
  - Death of DR. A. H. Salisbury: Papers removed from Bibleletters, etc., see also #2, above. Bible shelved separately, see under "removed," below (Box 442, Folder 4)
  - Genealogical Material 5: New England typed material and re Potter, Vanneman, Pinney and Salisbury, (Notes ) (Box 442, Folder 5-17)
  - Census Records: Mostly data copied from. Salisburys et aL., New York (Box 442, Folder 6)
  - Census and Marriage Records: Data copied from, Ohio PA [also Indiana] (Box 442, Folder 7)
  - Middle West: As above, from IL, IA, IN, MI, MN, WI (Box 442, Folder 8)
  - South: As above, from SC, MS, LA, TX (Box 442, Folder 9)
  - West: As above, from CA, OR (Box 442, Folder 10)
  - Sue Salisbury Pentagon Papers: re family history, 1920s, 1950s, (Letters ) (Box 442, Folder 11)
  - Salisbury Family Tree: England and America lists of names, alphabetically and chronologically -- Extracts from assorted records re various American Salisburys (Box 442, Folder 12)
  - Families Compilations and Records: Salisburys and related, (Correspondence ) (Box 442, Folder 13)
  - Van Norman Assorted Genealogical Material (Box 442, Folder 14)
  - Van Norman Assorted Genealogy: Mostly Sue Salisbury, (Correspondence ) (Box 442, Folder 15)
  - Spear Family: Copied in a blue binder -- loose pp. re Spear, Salisbury etc., (Letter, Assorted Family Records ) (Box 442, Folder 16)
  - Basic Salisbury Genealogy: Mostly Sue's work, including sketched of upstate NY, census data, etc. re Salisbury, Van Norman families, (Maps, Correspondence ) (Box 442, Folder 17)
  - Genealogy: Deanes et aL.material re Deane, Potter, Anthony, Briggs, Carr, Cogan, Copeland, Dighton, Earle, Fisher, Gilbert, Rossiter, Williams (Box 443, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Genealogy: Including JES application for Children of the American Revolution, (Notes, Corresponedence ) (Box 443, Folder 19)
  - Susan Salisbury Genealogy (Box 443, Folder 20)
  - For Farrell Dobbs Memorial: By Salisbury -- Lindbergh's "Own Story", Nov 20, 1983, (Antidue Cards, Birthday Cards, Christmas Card, Pamphlets ) (Box 443, Folder 21)
  - AHS Home Encyclopedia On Care Of The Child: Draft, written in Mazomanie [WI], 1870s (Box 443, Folder 22)
  - AHS University of Michigan (1865), U. of Wisconsin (1865), U. of Minnesota (1893) -- Minneapolis Industrial Exposition, 1886, (Mementoes, Programs, Various Events, Stock Certificate ) (Box 443, Folder 23)
  - World's Fair Miniatures, 1904, (Commercial Souvenir, Photos ) (Box 443, Folder 24)
  - AHS Bills, Mortgages: Some of James Pritchard1869 - 1901 (Box 443, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous: Four old-style leather wallets, one with label, "DR. A. H. Salisbury X'mas 1879" -- [Removed: Anna Augusta von Helmholtz - Phelan, The Crystal Cup, inscribed by author "with affection for my dear former student, Harrison Salisbury" -- "My Friends' Birthdays" -- inscription mostly illegible, 1887 -- Bible -- large, undated -- w/ picture frame pages in back -- AH and Mary Pritchard Salisbury, 2 others -- Salisbury college note (4), w / title "Record" -- A H Salisbury Scrapbook 1884-89] -- [Removed: Pentagon Papers Salisbury high school diploma, 1889 -- Pentagon PapersS promotion to Sgt, University Corps of Cadets, 1890 -- rolled together -- AHS and Mary Pritchard marriage certificate, 1868 (rolled tightly, torn)], (Documents, Books, Photos, Wallets, Marriage Certificate ) (Box 443, Folder 26)
  - Guide to Historic Dane County: William Kittle, History of the Township and Village of Mazomanie [WI] (Madison, WI: State Journal Publishing CO.), 1990, (Books, Pamphlets ) (Box 444, Folder 1)
  - Divided Twins: Alaska and Siberia: NY: Viking, 1988. Removed from: Yevgeny Yevtushenko, 1988, (Publicity Material, Books ) (Box 444, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Video cassettes (not numbered or foldered): "The Great Wall of Iron" Promo 2 NTSC -- The Great Wall of Iron: ProG. 2 "Defying the Foreign Devils" BBC -- The Great Wall of Iron: "The People's Army?" (Programme 1) for transmission 6/29/89 BBC -- "The Kwitny ": Leningrad TV Footage 2 -- Atlanta Historical Society Livingstone Lectures, "Reflections on World War II" Salisbury 3/30/89 -- "Faces of the Enemy: for KQED/PBS to air 5/27/87 -- "Harvest of Despair" -- "After the War" a 56-minute ary or commemorate the Marshall Plan (with producer's to Salisbury, 5/2/7/87) -- "Frozen in Amber" with shipping from International Comunication Agency -- 2 tapes labelled in Chinese or Japanese, (Document, Letter, Report, Tapes ) (Box 444)
  - Miscellaneous Audio cassettes (not numbered or foldered): On "The War Between Russia and China" [Salisbury] -- American/Russian Writers Conference November 1985, Vilnius, Lithuania -- People in the Public Eye -- Al Beard 3/17/88 -- Larry King Show 3/14/88 (2 s) -- #3 Cross-Country Check-up, 2/12/84 -- CBC, NY -- CBC, Montreal -- Panorama June 2, 1983 -- Salisbury Mississippi on Catledge, Salisbury talk re Turner Catledge (New York Times) at Mississippi State -- With to Salisbury 4/14/86 -- Keeping up with the Times -- International Communism in the 1970s, By Harrison E. Salisbury, with printed brochure of contents [see also Box C83-1, folder 4 for], (Letter, Tapes, Books, Transcript ) (Box 445)
  - Harrison Salisbury Memorial Service, [n.p.], 14 September 1993, (1 videocassette) (Box 445)
  - A New Russia? -- Some in Russian, Apr 1962 (Box 446, Folder 1)
  - A New Russia?, (Proofs ) (Box 446, Folder 2)
  - Behind the Lines -- Hanoi: Edited with diagram of page layout, (Mss. ) (Box 446, Folder 3)
  - Behind the Lines -- Hanoi: 2 copies, (Proofs ) (Box 447, Folder 4)
  - Behind the Lines -- Hanoi: Ms -- typescript with corrections in pencil and ink (Box 447, Folder 5)
  - New York Times Russia in Times - EB Series: For volume on Russia in New York Times - Encyclopedia Britannica series on the world, 1964, (Mss., Correspondence ) (Box 447, Folder 6)
  - Behind the Lines -- Hanoi: Carbon copy, no corrections, P. 147 missing, (Mss. ) (Box 447, Folder 7)
  - Behind the Lines -- Hanoi: Carbon copy pp. and with corrections, P. 75 missing, (Photocopy, Mss. ) (Box 447, Folder 8)
  - Literature and Art, May 1964, (Clippings, RFE/RL Material, Congressional Hearings ) (Box 448, Folder 1)
  - Personnel: Mostly clips material from RFE/RL, Soviet Embassy, 1959-1960, (Dispatches, Notes, Clips ) (Box 448, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Khrushchev 70 [70th b'day] -- Agriculture, Yugoslavia, Schools, ReligionRFE/RL, etc., May 1964 (Box 448, Folder 3)
  - Soviet Union: -- RFE/RL: Military, 1962, (Newspaper, Notes ) (Box 448, Folder 4)
  - A New Russia -- Youth and Literary -- RFE/RL and Institute -- Outline for translation from Russian (not by Salisbury) (Box 448, Folder 5)
  - Soviet Political and Intelligentsia Shub series, mostly pre-1970 -- Semichastny, Yegoreychev, MVD, Pospelov, Police, Podgorny, Ceaucescu, Togliatti, Testament, Shelepin, Rajk trial, Starobin on '56, Neo-Stalinism newspaper, RFE/RL, etc. (Box 448, Folder 6)
  - RFE Material: Religion, Anti-semitism, 1962 (Box 449, Folder 7)
  - Ideology: English, Russian and German -- RFE/RL, Embassy, otherS, 1967, (Printed Material, Clippings, Statements, Newspapers, Journals ) (Box 449, Folder 8)
  - Economics, 1959-1960, (RFE Papers, Other Studies ) (Box 449, Folder 9)
  - Russia Miscellaneous Khrushchev, power politics, etc. -- Some Salisbury stories, FBIS, RFE, Embassy and others, 1962-63 (Box 449, Folder 10)
  - Soviet Union: -- Soviet Economy: AG. 1963, 1/64RFE and other published sources, 1956, 1963-4, 1963 (Box 450, Folder 11)
  - Biogs: Bulganin, Molotov, Kikoyan, Kaganovich, Khrushchev, Pospelov [et al] Salisbury profiles (printed and )of SoV. leaders, some profiles by others (many of these are done as advance obituaries for New York Times, (Mss., Notes, Profiles ) (Box 450, Folder 12)
  - Soviet Political and Intelligentsia: CR. Tatars, Yesenin-Volpin, Yakir, Chalidze, Galich, GalanskovRFE/RL and other published material. Also material re economy, religion, etc. -- Copy of Sakharov to Andropov 1973 (in Russian and English). Some in Russian, 1972, (Letter ) (Box 450, Folder 13)
  - Russia in Revolution: Picture Textapparently complete -- Original typescript pp. with corrections and photocopied pp. -- either out of order or misnumbered, (Photocopy, Book, Mss. ) (Box 450, Folder 14)
  - Russia in Revolution, (Caption, Captions, Photos, etc. ) (Box 450, Folder 15)
  - Postcards, Souvenir: 19th-century advertising and souvenir cards incL. 1886 ST. Paul Winter Carnival -- Envelope addressed to Maria L. C. Evans (Salisbury' grandmother), postmarked 1912 (Box 451, Folder 1-6)
  - Theatre Programs, 1881-1923, (Other Souvenirs ) (Box 451, Folder 2)
  - Family Register: of Hiram and Diana Ross Salisbury (M1820) (Box 451, Folder 3)
  - 17th Century Nun's Prayer: Copy, printed as poster (Box 451, Folder 4)
  - Notes: Salisbury removed from: Tocqueville, Democracy in America (Vintage pB., 1959) more Salisbury on title page --- shelved separately (Box 451, Folder 5)
  - re Salisbury Press, Buffalo -- removed from: Bruce Swift, The Story of the Salisbury Press (Buffalo: Wm J. Keller, InC.), 1954 -- Autographed -- shelved separately (Box 451, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous: -- Plastic bag with hair: (1) "Braids from sister Eunice's hair, OcT. 14th, 1889 -- died OcT. 13th/ satin bow from her slipper/ 19 yR. old" and "brown hair -- Father's JaN. 1890, died Jan 7th" (2) in separate paper, "Janet's 1st cut 1910" (barely legible) -- Box with pieces of sealing wax -- Box with assorted (rubber) stamps, incL. AHSalisbury signatures -- Seals, and engravings (including "Harrison Evans Salisbury" on copper plate -- Chinese medal in brocade-covered box -- Box of Salisbury bookplates -- Woodblock with face and name "Harrison" -- Medal in box: The Lotus Club 1870 -- Expo 70 (Japan?) tie bar and pin (in box) -- Plexiglass cube with design -- Scrap of paper with "900 Days" pin (in Russian) -- Pin with Chinese script, face of Mao -- Bendable clown doll -- US-China relations button, 1979 -- Scrap of paper with fraternity pin -- Medal: World Affairs Council of Philadelphia -- Reverse: "The William L. Batt Memorial Lecture Harrison E. Salisbury May 14, 1974" -- Soviet insignia with hammer and sickle on red star, etc. -- Straw coin purse (probably Chinese) (Box 451)
  - Miscellaneous: -- Inscribed to The ST. Nicholas Anthology (Random House, 1948), inscribed to Michael from Dad, 3/4 -- North High School Year (Polaris), 1925, with many signatures -- The Badger (U. of Wisconsin YrbK.) 1891, with name "AHSalisbury" written on 1st page -- A. J. Russell, Goodbye Row (Minnetonka Record Press, 1943, PB.), inscribed to Salisbury by author -- Bill Holm, The Music of Failure (Plains Press, 1985), inscribed to Salisbury by author, 3/31/87 -- Farrell Dobbs, Teamster Politics (NY: Monad Press, 1975), inscribed to Salisbury by author -- Farrell Dobbs, Teamster Bureaucracy (NY: Monad, 1977), inscribed to Salisbury by author -- James Taylor Dunn, Marine on ST. Croix: From Lumber Villlage to Summer Haven 1838-1968 (Marine Historical Society, 1968), inscribed to Salisbury by author -- Steve Richards, The Biggest Sycamore: Some Jackson Countiana (1948), Copy #2, inscribed to Salisbury: The University of Missouri (150 Years, 1989, "Presented with deep appreciation to Harrison E. Salisbury on the Occasion of the Enid Jackson Kemper Lecture in International Affairs at the University of Missouri on April 2, 1990" -- Bruce Weir Benidt, The Library (Centennial of Minneapolis Public Library, 1985), inscribed to Salisbury by author, (Book, Newspaper ) (Box 451)
  - Soviet Union: -- Yuri Kuper, Moskovskii Natiurmort: Moscow Still-Life, (Manuscript in Russian ) (Box 452, Folder 1)
  - Soviet Union: -- Soviet Literary Deutscher piece on "Che" faction in Mosparty, and journal (in English, Russian, and French) -- New York Times, 1961 (Box 452, Folder 2)
  - Soviet Union: -- Soviet Intellectuals & Literary Dissidence Yevtushenko, Vosnesensky (important texts), Khrushchev's son's eulogy at father's grave ['71], Yakir, Tarrasuk [refusenik] case, Galanskov, Chalidze newspaper: Sakharov and other dissident material (English and Russian) -- RL material, 1972-1974 (Box 452, Folder 3)
  - Soviet Union: -- Soviet General and Literary: Sakharov status, Chukovskaya, Galich, Bukovsky, Gomulka Reminiscences, P. Litvinov, Superfin, copyright RL, Khronika information, other material by and about Soviet dissidents. Some in Russian, 1973-1974, (Dispatches, Bulletins ) (Box 453, Folder 4)
  - Vietnam I Reaction German, and French -- Including copy of to AOS from Walter Lippman, copy of Walter Cronkite to Pulitzer committee re Salisbury, to Salisbury from J. W. Fullbright re Senate testimony, 1/24/67Some in Russian (Box 454, Folder 1)
  - Propaganda Pamphlets: Mostly VN publications in English, including of Vietnam -- Some material in French, Vietnamese and some Western and Japanese, etc. -- Les Accords de Geneve (Extraits), Hanoi, 1966-1967, (Maps, Newspapers, Reports ) (Box 454, Folder 2)
  - RFE, Vietnam, 1970 (Box 454, Folder 3)
  - Secondary Documents, Vietnam, 1966-1967 (Box 454, Folder 4)
  - George Palmer Replies [New York Times]: AssT. to the Managing Editor (mostly unfavorable), Hanoi, 1967, (Letters ) (Box 455, Folder 5)
  - Readers' Comments on Hanoi A-L: w/ Salisbury replies (mostly favorable), (Reports, Letters ) (Box 455, Folder 6)
  - Readers' Comments on Hanoi M-Z: Similar to #6, (Reports ) (Box 455, Folder 7)
  - Ho Chi Minh Death: Vietnamese and US re Ho's death and related, Paris Hanoi, Nov 18, 1969, (Dispatch, Reports ) (Box 455, Folder 8)
  - Sullivan, (7" reels: Tape 1 ) (Box 456)
  - Becket (Box 456, Folder 2)
  - Wash: Week 11-12 (Box 456, Folder 3)
  - Thompson (Box 456, Folder 4)
  - Huxtable (Box 456, Folder 5)
  - Curtis (Box 456, Folder 6)
  - Robert Rooso, May 28, 1970 (Box 456, Folder 7)
  - Lindsay/ Salisbury, May 14 (Box 456, Folder 8)
  - Ehrlich (Box 456, Folder 9)
  - Don Gibson: Look Who's Back (Box 456, Folder 10)
  - Yulya Songs of Russian Street Urchins, 1964 (Box 456, Folder 11)
  - Harrison Salisbury On Khrushchev (Box 456, Folder 12)
  - Fuller (Box 456, Folder 13)
  - Javits (Box 456, Folder 14)
  - WQXR/Atkinson. Tape 15 (Box 457)
  - Scoville (Box 457, Folder 16)
  - Atkinson (Box 457, Folder 17)
  - Pollak (Box 457, Folder 18)
  - Reston (Box 457, Folder 19)
  - Humphrey (Box 457, Folder 20)
  - Lilienthal (Box 457, Folder 21)
  - Harriman (Box 457, Folder 22)
  - Rosenthal (Box 457, Folder 23)
  - Moses (Box 457, Folder 24)
  - Greta Keller: Sings 12 Songs of Yulya, 1966 (Box 457, Folder 25)
  - Kennedy Lecture Series: Harrison Salisbury, "US Foreign Policy and the News", July 1, 1969 Ohio University, Athens, OH (Box 457, Folder 26)
  - Special Reel I: H. Salisbury, MIT Sakharov (Box 457, Folder 27)
  - Reel II: Salisbuy (Box 457, Folder 28)
  - Reel III: Salisbury. Tape 29 (Box 458)
  - Moscow NO. I: Julie's, (Tapes ) (Box 458, Folder 30)
  - Moscow, NO. II: Julie's (unnumbered) Yulya -- Midnight in Moscow (commercial recording, sealed), Smaller, (Tapes ) (Box 458, Folder 31)
  - The 900 Days: Leningrad of CBC, with note to Salisbury, Apr 21, 1969, (Tapes, Interview ) (Box 458, Folder 32)
  - Sanders/ Harrison Salisbury Major War: Asst Managing Editor, New York Times, says next will be between Russia and China (5") (Box 458, Folder 33)
  - : Pismo k Mao, Leningradskaya Blokada/ V. Vysotskii -- Nachalniki/ M. Nozhin -- 2nd track: Tam na Kladbishche/ M. Nozhin (3") (Box 458, Folder 34)
  - Penthouse - 30: Harrison Salisbury Rev (Box 458, Folder 35)
  - ERC Lecture: H. Salisbury (5"), Oct 31, 1968 (Box 458, Folder 36)
  - Tapes, 6 Sealed Boxes: Probably blank (Box 458)
  - Bears Are Sleeping: Words and Music by Yulya, Pictures by Nonny Hogrogian Armand Michel, L'Assassinat de John Kennedy: Le Rapport Warren et Ses Critiques (Trinkvel, 1968) -- boxed, (Books ) (Box 458)
  - , 1944-1949 (Box 459, Folder 1)
  - , 1954-1957 (Box 459, Folder 2)
  - The Last Days of Stalin First draft of play by David Karp, 1958 (Box 460, Folder 3)
  - Bolshoi Ballet w/ Salisbury piece about Galina Ulanova and issues of Novoye Vremya, 1959 (Box 460, Folder 4)
  - , 1960 (Box 461, Folder 5)
  - , 1961 (Box 461, Folder 6)
  - , 1962 (Box 461, Folder 7)
  - , 1963 (Box 461, Folder 8)
  - Piece on JFK Assassination The Passion of Josef D (Paddy Chayefsky), Salisbury with Chayefsky, of play, 1964 (Box 462, Folder 9)
  - Congressional Record In Russian, 1965 (Box 462, Folder 10)
  - 8 x 10, b&w of Salisbury with unidentified others (possibly Mongolian), 1966 (Box 462, Folder 11)
  - The Death of JK Script, compiled by W. N. Knight. Including in German, Danish, Swedish, 1967 (Box 462, Folder 12)
  - Mss.: Pp. 67-109 of unidentified in Russian (Box 463, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper, Notes: Salisbury (handwritten) and Russian, 1965 (Box 463, Folder 2)
  - In Russian (Box 463, Folder 3)
  - Mixnotes of Conversations, 1979-1985 (Box 463, Folder 4)
  - Radio Liberty Text: Salisbury on Khrushchev (Box 463, Folder 5)
  - Photocopy, Book, Notes: In Russian, with Salisbury Nikolai II: Materialy dlia Kharakteristiki Lichnosti i Tsarstvovaniya, Moscow, 1917 (Box 463, Folder 6)
  - Metropolitan Nikolai Photograph with Harrison Salisbury at airport, with protesters, New York, [n.d.] (Box 463)
  - Interview, Correspondence, Notes, Important Mixed Notes, 1976-1978 (Box 463, Folder 7)
  - World's Fair Lead: Section from Chicago Sunday Times, type block -- New York Times banner, w/ Salisbury as Associate editor, 1933, (Photographs ) (Box 463, Folder 8)
  - Libel Trial, (Clips, Photocopies, Books, Newspaper, Notes, Reviews ) (Box 464, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: Leningrad quotes from 900 Days, with b&w by Fumiko Kuwayama, (Album Pages ) (Box 464, Folder 10)
  - Henry Smith The Smiths of Moscow, (Letters, Photocopy, Contents, Outline ) (Box 464, Folder 11)
  - CBS Morning Show, 1976 (Box 464, Folder 12)
  - Behind the Lines: re Salisbury PBS series, 1975, (Correspondence ) (Box 465, Folder 13)
  - CIA, 1993 (Box 465, Folder 14)
  - New York Times Kennedy Shooting Copy: And others re RFK shooting, many in multiple copies, (Dispatches ) (Box 465, Folder 15)
  - Some in German, 1968 (Box 466, Folder 1)
  - On Mongolia, 1969 (Box 466, Folder 2)